[Music]
You all know about health insurance,
which requires you to buy health
insurance from some private company or
some government company,
and it covers all your physical ailments like
heart issues, stomach issues, fractures,
accidents, etc.
But is there dental
insurance in our country? This
question remains in everyone's mind: whether
dental insurance is available or not, or when will it be available?
I am Dr. Sahil Singh, a consultant
dentist at V Medical Clinics, and
today I will tell you whether dental
insurance is available or not, and if it is
available, to what extent is it available? First of all, under
government schemes
like CGHS, ECHS, ESI,
all the treatment options, be it for your dental or overall general health, are
available to you. Maximum
treatment options are available. So, it happens
that government
employees, their children, or
their dependents get the
benefits of government health schemes.  It can be availed but those who are
not in government jobs, who are
in private jobs, there are two-three different ways to include dental insurance or dental
treatment in their insurance.
Firstly, the insurance that corporate employees get, whether it is
dental or general health, they
can get treatment of about 10-100 rupees per month or year on OPD basis,
by getting those reimbursements they get tax benefit,
so this is one way, secondly for those who are
not corporate employees and do not have corporate
insurance, in the
new insurances which have been launched in India especially after Covid, in that
about Rs 5000 per month or Rs
5100 per year in some small insurances, you
can convert it into OPD or
use it for OPD, in which you can get
dental treatment or your medical
treatment, you can get any diagnostic test done,
you can get your blood tested,
you
can get reimbursements for any of these things from the insurance company by taking the bills for those.  Yes,
this is one way that till the time dental
insurance is not available in this country,
we can get some of our expenses borne
by the Renners Insurance Company and I
hope that in future dental insurance comes so that the
oral health of our country becomes
much better and also very affordable. Keep
smiling and take
care.